# Sophie Miller

Phone: (425) 210-4447 Seattle, WA

Email: millersq47@gmail.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sophie-garner-miller/ GitHub: https://github.com/millersq47 | Portfolio: https://millersq47.github.io/Sophie-Portfolio/

# Summary

Driven and curious Full Stack Web Developer with an interest in writing elegant code in collaborative settings, who seeks out opportunities for continuous improvement and learning. Pivoting from a career in project management to software engineering bringing experience with agile methodologies, project scheduling and creative problem solving.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Applications: Microsoft Word/Excel/SharePoint/OneNote/Dynamics, JIRA, WordPress, Shopify, Asana, Smartsheet, Photoshop /

Indesign / Illustrator

Tools: Epicor ERP, Bootstrap, Bulma, jQuery, Node.js, Semantic HTML, SQL, MySQL, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars

## **Projects**

**StarParty** | https://github.com/millersg47/StarParty | https://millersg47.github.io/StarParty/

**Summary:** This application delivers the weather forecast and various relevant astronomy information to a user based on their city input.

**Responsibilities:** Worked with another contributor on the Javascript files. I wrote all code in the landing.js file, wrote functions to fetch from the Nasa APOD API in the main.js file, and wrote all localStorage code in the main.js file.

**Technologies Used:** HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bulma, Google Fonts, Nasa APOD API, OpenWeather API, Geocoding API, Visible Planets API

#### Day Planner | https://github.com/millersg47/day-planner | https://millersg47.github.io/day-planner/

**Summary:** This application provides the user with a day planner breaking out their day into hour long blocks from 9 AM to 6 PM. The user can add notes of items that need to be accomplished or events that are happening during each hour block.

**Responsibilities:** Contributed to the Javascript, HTML and CSS file. Also updated the CSS sheet to add polished, custom UI. Implemented localStorage.

**Technologies Used:** HTML, CSS, Javascript, moment.js, Google Fonts, Font Awesome, Bootstrap

#### Code Quiz | https://qithub.com/millersq47/code-quiz | https://millersq47.github.io/code-quiz/

**Summary:** This application is a code quiz game for the user to test their knowledge of the Javascript language in a timed, game setting.

**Responsibilities:** Set up the HTML, CSS and Javascript for this program to make a responsive, interactive quiz for the user, storing inputs in localStorage and manipulating the DOM to cycle through all questions. Implemented timer functionality using the setInterval method.

**Technologies Used**: HTML, CSS, Javascript

# Experience

**Project Manager II** 2019 - 2020; 2021 - 2022

Taphandles Seattle, WA

- Build relationships with key account contacts, and owns the product development process to exceed partner needs
- Develops and maintains project-specific documentation including project roadmaps, trackers, and budget analysis as well as key internal data sets
- Using tools including Smartsheet, JIRA, Epicor ERP system, Microsoft Teams and Power BI to execute projects and match or exceed KPI goals
- Oversee client projects through entire lifecycle from project planning and budgeting through fulfillment

• launched a training and resource site when remote work became the norm and adapted outdated budget and pricing tools to improve efficiency

Account ManagerMAY 2020 - DECEMBER 2020The StableSeattle, WA

- Managed dedicated clients' e-commerce business on Amazon, working to grow their top line through inventory
  management, listing optimization and strategy recommendations; implemented product launches onsite,
  executing real-time solutions to boost revenue and managing the creative content development for listing
  pages, brand stores and A+ content
- Steered projects across multiple internal teams to produce high-quality deliverables meeting our clients' deadlines, including cross-functional projects with advertising, creative and e-commerce teams

Marketing CoordinatorMARCH 2019 - DECEMBER 2019TaphandlesSeattle, WA

- Developed digital and print collateral in collaboration with Creative Director, used internal ERP system as well as Trello and JIRA to manage workflow and produced onbrand deliverables within deadline and under budget
- Owned process development within the Marketing Department, making proposals to leadership and establishing best practices in the following areas: trade show presence, brand guidelines and social media
- Expanded e-commerce presence to Amazon Seller Central, managed product listings and campaigns, and coordinated internal product development preparing for launch resulting in year-over-year e-commerce revenue growth of 28%

## Education

## University of Washington – *Coding Boot Camp Certificate*

24-week program of intensive study and hands-on practice gaining technical programming skills including HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Node.js and React

Western Washington University — **Bachelor of Arts, Journalism**Minor in International Business